Derek Nelson

I want to write clean, maintainable code and have a good time doing it.

In my free time, I like to port Board games to the internet. Currently working on an app to help with Meal Prepping. I love hackathons and have three Top 3 finishes and a 1st place at Startup Weekend events. I have worked on games that

Technologies

Java, JavaScript, PHP, Spring, ExpressJS, PhaserJS, Angular 1-2, Gradle, Webpack, Ansible, Salt, Linux, Docker

placed 5th overall and 2nd in gameplay at the University of Michigan Global Game Jam.

Employment History

Zix/AppRiver – Software Engineer/Team Lead/Scrum Master

My time was split between development and DevOps. I worked with AppRiver on their email security platform SecureTide. I was a team lead at Zix and spent time as a Scrum Master at AppRiver.

Tech: Ruby, C#, Python, Mongo, Salt, Linux, AWS

Learning A-Z – Cambium Learning Group – Software Engineer 3

May 2013 - October 2018

Lead developer of a placement test for the Headsprout project which determined new students starting level and runs on the web, iOS, and Android. Developed a new user management system for Kurzweil 3000 administrators, used by thousands of schools. *Tech: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Java, Ant, PHP, Angular 1.x, MySQL*

Supply Chain Management - England Logistics - Software Engineer 3

2012 - 2013

Worked primarily on the audit and pay system. Wrote front-end interfaces in Google Web Toolkit and later in Angular. Used python script to automate importing bills into the legacy system. Maintained indexes for Lucene and CouchDb. *Tech: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Java, Angular 1.x, CouchDb, Lucene, Spring 3.x, Maven*

Admissions Department - Ferris State University - Web Developer

2010-2012

Wrote the admissions application for non-traditional students. Created an interactive map for students to find the Admissions officer for their region. For the Mobile site, I used Google Maps API to give students directions to the admissions building from anywhere on campus.

Tech: Html, CSS, Javascript, ColdFusion, BackboneJS, ¡Query, Microsoft SQL Server

Jung Choi (Professor) - Ferris State University - Teacher's Assistant

2011-2012

College of Business – Ferris State University – Web Developer

2009-2010

Maintained the College of Business website. Created new pages for events and programs using ColdFusion, Microsoft SQL Server, and JavaScript.

Tech: Html, CSS, Javascript, ColdFusion, BackboneJS, jQuery, Microsoft SQL Server

Computer Technology Services – Ferris State University – Support Technician

2008-2009

Mac and administrative support technician. Added and removed software. Troubleshooting hardware and software problems.

Animal Care Facility – Ferris State University – *Volunteer Web Developer*

2007-2008

Created a web application in PHP and MySQL to keep track of animals for a Pharmacy lab.

Tech: Html, CSS, PHP, MySql

Education

Ferris State University 2006-2011